前情提要
Previously on Future Man...
我们要速战速决  启动伽玛预案
This is a rush job, Gamma protocol.
她的小脑瓜还有26分钟就爆炸了
Her little head's going to blow in 26 minutes!
我发现了追溯到
I discovered a whole branch to my family tree
几百年前的一个家族分支
going back hundreds of years.
你到底对虎有多少了解
What do you really know about Tiger?
对这所谓的反抗组织有多少了解
About the socalled Resistance?
她根本不在乎婴儿
She doesn't care about babies.
她没有家人
She doesn't have a family of her own.
她和任何人任何东西都没有联系
She's not connected to anyone or anything.
我都被你们整糊涂了
I'm getting very confused right now.
别听她的  她生来就被设定成蛊惑人心
Don't listen to her, okay?  She is programmed to deceive.
卡素是以詹姆斯·卡梅隆命名的吗
Cameronium is named after James Cameron?
你刚告诉了我何时何该如何
You just told me how, when, and where
去获得更多的卡素
to get more Cameronium.
我要为他们的未来而战
I'm fighting for their future.
不是你的
Not yours.
所以你在接下来的30秒里
So why don't you contemplate that
好好思考吧
in the next 30 sec...
好了
Okay.
就是这里
This is it.
我们跳进去  找到实验室
We jump in, find the lab,
拿到卡素
grab the Cameronium,
在这过程中别杀了詹姆斯·卡梅隆
and don't kill James Cameron in the process.
我从没见你那么专注过
I've never seen you this focused.
我们出发前你充过电吗
Did you get a charge in before we left?
XXX
Little necro charge?
什么  还有这回事
What? That's a thing?
- 太变态了  - 不是
- That's fucked up.  - No!
听着  我只是想
Listen, I'm just trying to get you two out of here
在生化人还没来  造成损害或是好事前
before the Biotics arrive and start causing
把你们俩送走
either harm or... or good,
我真的不能再确定了
I really can't be sure anymore.
虎她人呢
Where the hell is Tiger?
- 你去哪了  - 我刚让一个陌生人
- Where were you?  - I was just having a stranger
用她的小嘴含着我的老二
put a rat hole around my penis
在我本应执行干扰行动的时候
when I was supposed to be running an interference op.
不好意思  那是你
I'm sorry, that was you.
那叫口交
It's called a blowjob,
而且我绝不会为此道歉
and I'm never apologizing for it.
你应该意识到  如果这不起作用
You do realize that if this doesn't work,
我们就会被困在2023年  回不来了
we're stuck in the year 2023 and there's no coming back.
说实话  经历了今晚的事后
Honestly, after everything that happened tonight,
我真的无所谓了
I really don't give a shit.
开始吧
Let's do this.
今晚怎么了
Hey, what happened tonight?
你脑子短路了吗
Are you out of your fucking mind?
好了
Okay.
我真的不知道你在说什么
I genuinely have no idea  what you're talking about,
但你也许应该注意下你的态度
but you might want to check that attitude of yours
在那扇惊人的门前
at that very impressive door.
欢迎光临
Hello and welcome.
请原谅我
Please accept my apologies.
我不知道屋里来了客人
I was unaware there were guests in the house.
我会执行一次全面诊断
I will run a full diagnostic
来判断出错的原因
to determine the cause of this error
确保不会再次发生
to ensure it does not happen again.
别冲动
stand down.
卡梅隆一定装了智能房屋之类的东西
Cameron must have, like, a smart house or something.
- 这不是真的人  - 这他妈是什么
- It's not a real person.  - What the fuck is it, then?
这就是个声音
It's... it's just a voice,
就像是没有身躯的机器人
it's like a robot without a body.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是住宅和网络环境的
I am the Simulated Intelligence Guardian
虚拟智能卫士
of Residence and Network Environment,
但你能叫我西格尼
but you may call me SIGORNE.
请问你们是谁
To whom am I speaking?
我父亲和詹姆斯·卡梅隆是同事
My... my dad actually worked with James Cameron.
我是汤姆·阿诺德的儿子
I am... Tom Arnold's son.
欢迎  贾克斯·阿诺德
Welcome, Jax Arnold,
为你送上迟到的十岁生日祝福
and a happy belated tenth birthday.
我是个四年级的小学生
I'm a fourth grader.
你还有同伴吗
And you are accompanied by?
保姆们
Babysitters!
向你的儿童看护专家们问好
And greetings to your childcare professionals.
西格尼  詹姆斯·卡梅隆在哪
Hey, SIGORNE,  when is Mr. Cam... James...
不对  是詹姆叔叔在家吗
Uncle Jim returning home?
优秀电影制作人詹姆斯·卡梅隆正在
Awardwinning filmmaker  James Cameron is at.
克鲁尼州长家中
Governor Clooney's residence  for a private screening
放映他万众期待的阿凡达5
of his hotly anticipated Avatar 5.
棒极了
Awesome.
- 这对乔治市是件好事  - 是的
- And good for George.  - Yes.
作为第一先生  他对艾莫·克鲁尼州长的
As First Husband, he has considerable influence
社交日程有很大的影响力
on the social calendar of Governor Amal Clooney.
我们能不能在詹姆叔叔回家前
Hey, is there any chance that we could get a tour
去他的实验室逛逛
of Uncle Jim's lab before he gets home?
抱歉  但贾克斯·阿诺德和儿童看护专家们
I'm sorry, but Jax Arnold and childcare professionals
在JCC里并没有那样的权限
are not cleared for that level of the JCC,
也就是詹姆斯·卡梅隆的豪宅
the James Cameron Compound.
西格尼
Hey, SIGORNE.
你有没有想要
You think you might want to
休息一小会
take a break for a little while?
关机一下下
You know, turn yourself off?
我永远不会关机
There is no off.
伙计们
Hey... guys.
过来
Come here.
我觉得西格尼是个麻烦
I think SIGORNE's going to be a bit of a problem.
我们得关闭她
We need to shut her down.
沃夫  找到给她供电的主机
Wolf, find the mainframe that's powering her,
毁掉它
kill it.
我和西格尼无冤无仇的
Well, I got no beef with SIGORNE.
她听上去很有修养
She sounds tough and accomplished,
而且又亲切  又有母性
at the same time approachable, maternal.
我在这屋子里很有安全感
I feel safe in this house.
我不关心你的感觉
Okay, your feelings mean nothing to me.
你是爆破专家
You're the demolitions expert.
找到她的机械脑  然后炸飞它
Find her robot brain and blow it up.
如果我是房子
If I was a house,
我会把大脑放在哪
where would my brain be?
我去
Rad bot.
你在欣赏的武器原型
The weapon prototypes you're admiring
都是由多才多艺的
were all designed by groundbreaking
詹姆斯·卡梅隆设计的
multihyphenate James Cameron.
这家伙这牛
This guy!
对高于一般人的詹姆斯·卡梅隆来说
To tallerthanaverage James Cameron,
亲自去做异形一点都不难
there's nothing Aliens about getting your hands dirty.
他因身兼数职而为人所知
He has been known to wear many hats,
他的天赋涉及到多个领域
as his talents cannot be confined to one field.
等等
So... wait.
他一辈子都在专注一件事
He trained all his life to do one thing,
并且很拿手
was great at it,
然后又找到其他拿手的事
then found other stuff he was great at and he...
然后全做成了
and he did that too?
著名创新者詹姆斯·卡梅隆
Celebrated innovator James Cameron
有多重身份
has lived a dozen lives.
导演
Director,
慈善家
philanthropist,
少年棒球联合会的不败教练
undefeated Little League coach,
深海探索者
deepsea explorer,
婚姻高手
good at marriage.
还有很多  因为他真的是一个
The list goes on, for he is truly a...
超级天才
Titanic talent.
这个神圣的文字是什么
What sacred text is this?
是纳美语
It's Na'vi, the language
是空想语言学家詹姆斯·卡梅隆发明的
visionary linguist James Cameron invented.
二
Two.
四号走廊
Hallway number four.
心绪照明设为来势汹汹
Mood lighting set to ominous.
看上去就是变了灯光而已
Seems like it's just set to colored lighting.
知道吗
You know what?
你没法理解
You cannot possibly begin to understand
詹姆斯·卡梅隆的敏锐和天才
the subtleties and the genius of James Cameron.
我的理解是  他对蓝光情有独钟
What I understand it that he's got a hardon for blue lights.
拒绝访问
Access denied to...
微缩模型厅
Hall of miniatures.
拒绝访问
Access denied.